welcome back
today we are going to work on the stuff we had left over in the past episodes
since this stuff is also covered by quests
let's start by opening the next chapter of our book
after being reminded that we are entering the work in progress area
we find a quest that remind us of our hypogen needs
we quickly complete it
and then we get reminded on our main objective
a hypogen coil plasma forge
making 16 coils for the quest is easy
but we have no use for such low amount of coils
we need 2000 for our DTPF
or 900 for a blast furnace
and the next quest requires us to make space time
which is made in an hypogen plasma forge
so this path is blocked
on the other side
after pulverizing one of the tesaracts we made to test our DTPF
we obtained some transcendent metal dust
cooking that stuff is incredibly expensive
the process also requires some tungsten
that ends up becoming celestial in the process
and to cool it down
we have to add super coolant and titan steel to the freezer
while the reason is explained by the quest book
what we care about is that we now have the spiny ingot
and that was one of the two materials we needed for our space elevator upgrade
the other one is dimensionally shifted superfluid
this requires a bunch of things
but the first ingredient we notice is the next grade of purified water
and before we can even start looking at how that new purification unit works
we notice a lack of quarks
those are made in a cyclotron
so let's repurpose our quantum anomaly set up to a quark isolator one
once we obtained enough quarks
we notice one slightly bigger issue
to craft the purification plant structure
we need quite some diamonds
which are mostly going into making 100,000 infinity ingots
since we have a DTPF
it is probably a better option to use that instead
however
while that recipe make a lot of infinity
it is also eating a lot of resplendent catalyst
and that was with a 50 fuel discount
thanks to having fully breached the dimensional boundaries
by making hypogen and neutronium for 8 hours straight
which means that our current DTPF fuel production plant running on 350 amps UHV is not enough
so we push it even further
by doubling the amount of machines
while also wall sharing the expensive laser
but the first thing we will want to do with our new Infinity source is
upgrade our component assembly line
that way
we will be able to use less Infinity
for the components required for our upcoming machines
such as the blocks we needed for the last tier of water purification plant
those expensive components are also needed
in the catalyst that this plant works with
so after a day of intensively staring at our infinity stonks
we managed to stock up enough materials to craft the required parts
and after also getting the specialized quark catalysts
we are ready to purify our water at subatomic levels
as usual
we have to solve some logistical puzzle
to make that machine work
after some tests
we figured out that
this machine only cares about the sequence of inserted stuff
so we did some math analysis
to find an optimal sequence of stuff to insert
to find the correct combination as fast as possible
with that
it was just a matter of doing a little bit of Redstone circuitry
to properly manage the sequence loading and insertion
and here you can see the train of quark releasing catalysts being loaded up
and then inserted in a fixed order
and with that
we managed to obtain the subatomically perfected water
and the baryonic stabilized matter
which we merge into the dimensionally shifted superfluid
required for our new space elevator motors
with those
we can now run the Mining Modules MK3
capable of sending drones far enough to collect draconic cores
but for the moment we only found trash
so you know the drill
while the new drills are being forged
we can do some new quests
and since we still haven't done the new components
let's see how those are made
the new weird material we have to use to handle the strength of 33 millions volts is
proto-halkonite steel
to get that material
we start by coating an Infinity fine wire with a special blend of expensive materials
once the first coating is done
we complete the material by freezing some dimensionally shifted superfluid around it
after using this new material for all of the UIV components
we move on to the next the quest
new superconductor
and here we face a new issue
to work that stuff
we need an internal coil EBF or a hypogen coil DTPF
so you know the drill
we go do something else
luckily
it looks like our mining drones managed to find one draconic core schematic between all of the space trash
now we can craft draconic cores
and thus unlock the tier 2 fusion crafter
by the way
to get the required ichorium
we can now send a mining drone on some far asteroids to collect some
and then we quickly infuse it
thus upgrading our Fusion Crafter
which we then upgrade again with the Wyvern stuff
and with that
we can finally craft Dragon blood out of cheap stuff
the reason we did that was to get more hypogen
however
getting there took us quite some time
and in the meanwhile
our DTPF kept making hypogen to keep warm
making already enough of for the new coils we needed
and I got to say
solidifying that material is a really hard task
and after hours of solidifying screws
we managed to complete our new DTPF
as with the old one
to keep it warmed up
we set it up to make hypogen whenever there are no craftings queued up
and this one with hypogen coils
can do the recipe that has twice the yield
and it can also do new materials
such as space time
with that
we can finally craft crafting input buffers
which will allow us to make better looking crafting setups
this input will indeed contain both solids and fluids
have infinite caching
and separate the materials of the various recipes
but running 2 DTPF is starting to put too much of a strain on our generators
to boost our production
we are going to throw some hypogen in our fuel
and then we also add some of the leftover heavy radox from the radox polymer setup
and now it is time to see how our new fuel does
and it looks like it can fill up our battery in 3 weeks
with that extra production
we can even do a bit of overclocking on our DTPFs
to do so
we can use a screwdriver to remove the throttle we previously applied to the power plug
going back to our progression
we can now use our new DTPF for making the new UIV superconductor
which we use for the new energy hatches
next we could work on the final tier of coils
however those look quite expensive
not to mention
we won't get them with our current space time production
looking for a solution
we can try moving to the other quest branch
making a UMV circuit
which basically means just adding a new layer to our circuit factory
and behind that circuits hides a solution to our problems
with more power we can get spacetime faster
and the way we have to resort to get enough power at that stage
is by harvesting all of the energy emitted by a whole star
by building a Dyson sphere around it
and while the expensive parts of the structure are being crafted
we can work on the long chain of recursive crafts for modules we will be constantly launching in space
and here the main issue is two materials
which are not easy to come by
to get those
we can kidnap a couple of mobs
and get some armors out of their clones
however
some of the dropped armors are damaged
and our macerater doesn't like to recycle stuff that is not brand new
so to make it accept those items
we first have to repair them using an energetic infuser
once we have tidied the wardrobe
we can send it through an industrial maceration stack
and with that
we can now start stocking up modules
for our upcoming Dyson Sphere
meanwhile
the structure to launch those is not crafting properly
the teseracts are not crafting
and our DTPF is not working
the issue seems to be that we run out of fuel
our fuel plant indeed can't process fuel fast enough
the recipe has a base crafting time of almost 1 hour at UHV voltage
not once, but on multiple steps
to fix that issue
we can now afford a plasma mixer
that thing will do all of the steps in 5 seconds and with parallelization
but there are no discounts on the amount of power used
indeed this machine is so power intensive
that no cable or laser can power it
how do we make it run then
well
we can give it energy from the wireless network
which is a virtual battery
with virtually infinite power capacity
that high tier laptonic capacitor banks can swap energy with
once the energy is rebalanced with the wireless battery
we can use our mixer
but that didn't really fix the issue
we just move it to our fusion reactors
they can't keep up with all of those plasmas
and that is not the only fusion issue
we are also having trouble with the metastable oganesson production
which is made by our smaller Mark 4 reactors
to fix those problems
we should do a Mark 4 compact reactor
which will do higher parallels and
unlike its predecessors
has perfect overclocking
meaning it will be more than 16 times faster than the compact 3 on tier 1 plasmas
to craft it
we only lack of platinum and one of the plastics
usually to fix those issues
we would upgrade our stocking storage
or find the bottleneck in our processing chain
and speed it up
however
that is a task which has become hard to manage
and is starting to cause lag
and we now have a better solution
for those early game long processing chains
the quantum force transformer
can do the whole platline as a single recipient
can be easily overclocked and parallelized
and we won't have to work with any of the involved fluids
for the plastic
it won't simply do polybenzimidazole at once
it will also do all of the other simpler polymers at the same time
and here we have our new machine
making a lot of plastics in a single step
while our plastics are stocking up
we can make a second machine for processing platinum
and since this machine is super fast
even with low amount of catalyst and power
we can clean up the old platline
meanwhile
we have managed to gather all the ingredients required for our new fusion reactor
and after building some more machines to process everything
we managed to complete our new reactor
this reactor is so fast
that the bottleneck is now our plasma mixer
but we can quickly fix that issue
by increasing its maximum parallel
and letting it eat our whole battery
while the mixer waits for the leftover energy
to be sent into the wireless network
we can work on building more machines
to speed up the crafting speed of our Dyson Sphere
and we can even build machines in parallel
by using Loki Ring from the Funny Flower mod
and with all of those new machines
we quickly complete all of the parts of our new source of power
the Dyson Sphere
the issue of that structure
is that the modules we use to encase a star
can end up gliding and thus break
so we have to constantly feed new modules
and some computation to better calculate the module trajectories
lowering the needed replacements
to move all of that energy back to our base
we could craft one more really ultimate battery
but I think a wormhole generator sounds cooler
with that we now have enough power
to further speed up our hypogen production
with the power of 40,000 UHV amps
our production went from half ingot to more than 2 every second
to further increase our plasma forging capacity
we use the hypogen to multiply our DTPFs
and even with 4 DTPFs running at that power
we are still making less than one ingot of space time each second
however if we manage to get eternal coils
we can use a recipe that will use less than half the ingredients to make four times as much
the main issue is that eternal coils
other than requiring quite some space time
and a UIV circuit
also require an eternal singularity
getting these is quite expensive
and also needs some stuff
such as Soul Sand which we haven't really automated
when we needed a couple of blocks for a single singularity
it was doable
now we have to find a better way
and I think the best way is to not use soul sand at all
we can get a singularity by compressing a little bit of space time
however
that requires a stabilized black hole
which is a whole new rabbit hole to explore
and I think that is a good moment to
start working on that
since this is the last main quest of the current tier
so after working millions of iron dusts
we managed to build a structure
strong enough to support and contain a black hole
this machine has some peculiar requirements
first
we need a black hole seed to open a black hole
so we can compress stuff
once the black hole becomes too unstable
we close it with a collapsar
so once everything is ready
we can throw a black hole seed into the machine
and admire our creation
which we use to craft eternal singularities
however our black hole is going to slowly decay
thus becoming unusable for the task
and in that state
it is going to void our ingredients
so we make it collapse to clean up the machine
and now it is time to fully automate that process
after doing a little bit of math
we find out that
by also adding some extra stabilizer
we can craft a batch of 2800 singularities with a single black hole
so we quickly build a custom AE2 pattern
with all of the stuff that we will have to use
the items will be split
so that a group of timers can properly manage the black hole
the first one is going to let the black hole get close to the end of its lifespan
during this phase
the black hole will allow us to do 88 singularities at a time
then
just before the critical point
the timer will trigger a second timer
which will halt the decay of our black hole by inserting liquid space time inside it
the material costs grows exponentially
so
we do not want to let this process go on for too much time
and at this stage
our black hole will compress 350 items at once
and once the stabilizer cost becomes too high
we collapse the hole
now that we have enough singularities
we can start working on the last tier of heating coils
and that required us to build a new set of solidifiers
to get all of the ingots and screws
then our array of wire factories prepared the cabling
finally with all of our 14 generic purpose assembly lines
we slowly crafted the new coils
while we craft the 7000 coils required for the DTPF upgrade
we can also use the singularities for upgrading our ore facility
the issue is that we can't let our ore facility run
because it will quickly clog our storage room
but now we can afford better storage
and we are going to use it to stock up the stuff we are making in unlimited amount right on the production site
meanwhile
after fixing the AFK counter
we stocked up enough coils to upgrade our DTPFs
with those
we can now make cheaper space time
cheaper hypogen
one stack of Infinity out of a single catalyst
and many other latter game recipes
and with that
I think we can close this chapter
so what was the lesson of today's episode
always build your fusion reactors in a tunnel
for nice visuals
see you next time for even bigger multi blocks
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天要做的是前几集遗漏的东西
而它们也在任务中有提及
让我们从这本书的下一章开始
在被提醒我们进入半成品区后
这里有个任务需要海珀珍
我们快速完成它
然后我们想起了主要目标
海珀珍等离子锻炉
制作16个线圈完成任务很简单
但是这个量少得没用
我们的DTPF需要2112个
巨型高炉需要864个
下一个任务要求我们创造时空
它是在海珀珍DTPF中制造的
所以这条路行不通
另一方面
在粉碎了用来测试DTPF而制作的粗制超立方体后
我们得到了超时空金属粉
烧制那东西非常贵
这个过程还需要一些钨
在这个过程中最终变成了天体钨等离子体
而想让它冷却下来
我们得往冰箱里加超级冷却剂和泰坦精钢
虽然任务书解释了原因
我们关心的是有转转锭了
那是我们升级太空电梯所需的两种材料之一
另一个是纬度偏移超流体
这需要一堆材料
但是我们注意到的第一种成分是级八水
在我们开始研究新的净化装置如何工作之前
我们发现缺少夸克
这些都是用回旋加速器制造的
所以让我们把量子异常设备改成夸克分离器
一旦得到足够的夸克
我们又发现更严重一点的问题
要制作净化工厂的结构方块
我们需要相当多的钻石
主要用于制造十万个无限锭
既然我们有DTPF
使用它可能是一个更好的选择
然而
虽然这个配方产出大量的无尽
它也在吞噬大量的光辉催化剂
这甚至是在有50%的燃料折扣下发生的
这折扣是通过连续8小时制造海珀珍和中子
成功突破维度界限带来的
这意味着350A UHV耗能的燃料生产是远远不够的
所以我们更进一步
通过将机器数量增加一倍
同时共用昂贵的激光仓
不过有了更快更好的无限来源后的第一件事
是升级部件装配线
这样子
我们能用更少的无限锭
来生产即将到来的机器所需的组件
比如最后一级净水厂所需的方块
这净水厂的催化剂
也这需要价值高昂的材料
在密切关注无尽的库存后
我们储备了足够制作所需的部件的材料
在得到了特定的夸克催化剂后
我们已经准备好在亚原子层面上净化我们的水
像往常一样
我们必须解决一些物流问题
来让那台机器工作
经过一些测试
我们发现
这台机器只关心物品输入的序列
所以我们做了一些数学分析
找到一个最佳的输入序列
用来尽快找到正确的组合
有了那个
这不过是搭一些红石线缆
来管理序列正确加载和插入的问题
你可以看到一列夸克释放催化剂被装载起来
然后按固定顺序插入
有了这个
我们就得到了理想微粒水（八级水）
以及重子稳定物质
我们将其合并成维度偏移超流体
用来制作新的太空电梯加速轨道
用那些
我们现在可以运行采矿模块MK3
将无人机送到足够远的地方收集龙芯
但目前我们只找到垃圾
现在你知道下一步怎么“钻”了
当新钻头被锻造时
我们可以做一些新的任务
由于我们还没有完成新的组件
让我们看看这些是如何制作的
这种能够承载3300万伏的神必新材料是
原初恒坚钢
想获得它的话
我们首先用一种昂贵的材料涂抹细无尽导线
一旦涂层完成
我们通过在附近冻结超维度偏移超流体来完成材料
在将这种新材料用于所有UIV组件后
我们继续下一个任务
新的超导体
现在我们面临一个新问题
去生产那东西
我们需要一个永恒高炉或者海珀珍DTPF
接下来怎么办就很明白了
我们去做点别的
幸运地
看来我们的采矿无人机在所有太空垃圾之间
找到了一个龙芯示意图
现在我们可以制作龙芯了
从而解锁二级聚合机械方块
顺便说一下
为了获得所需的灵宝
我们可以通过太空钻机来挖一点
然后我们快速注魔
从而升级我们的龙研聚合
然后我们用双足飞龙再次升级
有了这个
我们终于可以用便宜的东西制作龙血了
我们这样做的原因是获得更多的海珀珍
然而
做出那些东西花了我们不少时间
与此同时
我们的DTPF一直在制造海珀珍来保持维度超越
新线圈材料已经足够
我不得不说
固化这种材料是一项非常艰巨的任务
经过数小时的固化螺丝
我们设法完成了新的DTPF
和旧的一样
让它保持运作
只要没有主动下单
就让它制作海珀珍
有了海珀珍线圈
可以用两倍产量的配方了
它还可以制造新材料
比如时空
有了那个
我们终于可以制作样板输入总成了
这让我们做出更好看的自动化方案
这个输入包含固体和液体
有无限缓存
并将各种配方的材料分开
但运行2个DTPF给发电机上太多压力了
为了提高发电量
我们要往燃料里加点海珀珍
我们还往燃料里勾兑了一些
从拉多聚合物中提取的重拉多X
现在是时候看看新燃料的能耐
看起来它可以在3周内充满我们的电池
有了这额外的发电
我们甚至可以在DTPF上做一点超频
为此
我们可以用螺丝刀移除之前在激光仓设置的上限
回到主线
我们现在可以使用新DTPF来制造新的UIV超导
将其用于新能源仓
接下来做最后一级线圈
然而，这些看起来很贵
更不用说
以我们现在的时空产量是远远不够的
寻找解决方案
我们可以尝试转移到另一个任务分支
制作UMV电路
这基本上意味着在我们的电路工厂中新添加一层
在电路的背后隐藏着解决问题的方法
有了更多的能量
我们可以更快地制造时空
在此阶段获得能量的最佳方法
是收集整个恒星发出的所有能量
通过在它周围建造一个戴森球
在昂贵的结构方块制作的同时
我们给将不断送入太空的模块的套娃合成自动化
主要问题是两种材料
这并不容易获得
为了获得它们
我们可以绑架几个怪
从他们的克隆体中得到一些盔甲
然而
一些掉落的盔甲损坏了
我们的粉碎机不喜欢回收旧物品
所以为了让它接受这些物品
我们首先得用能量注入器修复它们
一旦我们整理好衣柜
我们把它送入工业粉碎机
有了这个
对于即将到来的戴森球
我们可以开始储备模块了
同时
戴森球的结构方块并没有被正确制造
粗制超立方体并没有在制作
而且我们的DTPF也停止工作了
问题似乎是燃料用完了
我们的燃料工厂确实不够快
该配方在UHV下的基础制作时间大概是1小时
不止一步，好几步都这样
为了解决这个问题
我们可以推出等离子搅拌机了
它可以并行地在五秒内完成所有配方
但耗电量没有折扣
确实，这台机器是如此耗电
没有电缆或激光可以为它供电
那么我们如何让它运行呢？
实际上
我们可以从无线网络中为它提供能量
这是一个虚拟电网
具有几乎无限的功率容量
能够与高级电容交换电量
一旦能量与无线电网重新平衡
搅拌机便可以使用了
但这并没有真正解决问题
我们只是把问题转移到了聚变反应堆上
而它们生产等离子的速度跟不上了
这不是唯一的核聚变问题
我们也遇到了亚稳态鿫的生产问题
它们由小MK4反应堆制作的
为解决这些问题
我们应该做一个压缩聚变MK4
它拥有更高的并行
不同于前者
它能执行无损超频
在t1配方上，压聚4将比压聚3快16倍
要制作它
我们只缺铂金和一种塑料
这些问题的常规解法
是升级对应的缓存
或者是找到产线中的瓶颈
并加快速度
然而
这是一项已变得难以管理的任务
并且开始导致卡顿
我们现在有一个更好的解决方案
来处理那些前期的长产线
量子操纵者
它可以一步完成整条铂处理
可以轻松超频和并行
我们再也不用处理这些流体了
对于塑料
一次性不会只制作聚苯并咪唑
它也会同时做所有其他更简单的聚合物
这就是我们的新机器
一步就能产出大量塑料
当我们的塑料在囤积
我们可以制造第二台加工铂金的机器
由于这台机器速度非常快
即使催化剂很少、耗能很低
我们可以清理旧产线了
同时
我们已经收集到新聚变反应堆所需的所有材料
在建造更多机器来处理所有东西之后
我们完成了新的反应堆
这个反应堆可太快了
瓶颈现在已经是搅拌机了
但我们可以快速解决这个问题
通过增加其最大并行
让其使用我们所有的电力
当搅拌机等待剩余能量
被发送进无线网络时
我们可以制造更多的机器
加快戴森球的制作速度
通过使用植物魔法中的洛基戒指
我们甚至可以并行制造机器
有了这些新机器
我们很快就完成了新能源的所有部分
戴森球
这个结构的问题是
我们用来包裹恒星的模块
最终会滑行，从而破裂
所以我们必须不断地发射新模块
和更多算力来更好地计算模块轨迹
降低所需的替代品
要把所有的能量转移回基地
我们可以再制造一个真·终极电池
但我觉得虫洞发生器听起来更酷
这样我们就有了足够的能量
进一步加快海珀珍的生产
有了40000A的UHV电
产量从每秒半个锭上升至超过两个锭
为了进一步提高DTPF产能
我们用海珀珍来增加DTPF的数量
即使在该功率下运行4个DTPF
每秒时空产量也不到一个锭
但是如果我们能得到永恒线圈
我们可以用不到一半的原料做四倍的量
主要问题是永恒线圈
除了需要相当多的时空
和UIV电路
也需要一个永恒奇点
做这些东西很贵
而且还需要一些东西
比如我们还没有真正自动化的灵魂沙
只用几块灵魂沙做一个奇点
是完全可以接受的
现在我们必须找到更好的方法
我认为最好的方法是完全不使用灵魂沙
我们可以通过压缩一点时空得到奇点
然而
这需要一个稳定的黑洞
这又是一条不归路
我认为这是一个很好的时机……
来开始研究它
因为这是当前电压的最后一个主要任务
所以在处理了数百万个铁粉后
我们建立了一个结构
强大到足以支撑和容纳黑洞
这台机器有一些特殊要求
第一
我们需要黑洞种子来打开黑洞
这样我们就可以压缩东西了
一旦黑洞变得不稳定
我们用黑洞坍缩器来关闭它
所以一旦一切准备就绪
我们可以把黑洞种子扔进机器里
欣赏我们所创造的东西
我们用它来制造永恒奇点
然而我们的黑洞将慢慢衰变
逐渐无法继续生产
在那种状态下
它会吞噬我们的材料
所以我们让它坍缩来重置机器
现在是时候完全自动化这个过程了
在做了一点数学运算之后
我们发现
通过添加一些额外的稳定剂
我们可以用一个黑洞制造出2800个奇点
所以我们快速编写一个样板
包含了所有需要的东西
材料将被拆分
这样一组计时器就能妥善管理黑洞
第一个是让黑洞接近其寿命的终点
在此阶段
黑洞可以让我们一次产生88个奇点
然后
就在临界点之前
计时器将触发第二个计时器
它将通过在黑洞中插入熔融时空来阻止黑洞的衰变
材料成本指数增长
所以
我们不想让这个过程持续太久
而在这个阶段
我们的黑洞将一次压缩350个物品
一旦稳定器成本过高
我们就把黑洞坍塌
现在我们有足够的奇点了
我们可以开始研究最后一级线圈了
这要求我们建造一套新的固化器
来获得所有的锭和螺丝
然后我们的线缆厂准备好了电缆
最后是我们所有的14条通用装配线
我们慢慢制作新的线圈
当我们制作DTPF升级所需的7000个线圈时
我们也可以利用奇点来升级矿处
问题是我们不能让矿处运转
因为它会很快塞满存储元件
但现在我们可以负担得起更好的存储
我们将用它来储存产线中出产的近乎无穷的物品
同时
修好AFK计时器后
我们储备了足够的线圈来升级DTPF
用那些
我们现在可以制造更便宜的时空
廉价的海珀珍
从单一催化剂中取出一堆无尽
以及许多其他后期游戏配方
有了这个
我想我们可以结束这一章了
那么今天的教训是什么？
聚变反应堆应该造在隧道中
这可太好看了
下次见就会见到更多更大的多方块了
拜拜
（由于强相互作用的性质，实际上夸克是禁闭的，也就是无法分离出单个夸克）
（stonk是外网对stock的戏称）
（you know the drill 是双关：
常规用法 ： 你知道规矩 / 老套路了吧
字面意思 ： 钻头）